all right hello
everyone yes youtube and facebook
welcome to today's
oh i think this is actually just
facebook today hello facebook
uh welcome to today's project roundtable
yeah are we going to choose a beast just
now
let me do a little intro sure yeah i
guess we'll just give a quick
yeah if you want to give an intro to
project roundtables quick and then
yes so um we meet and we talk about kind
of what we've been doing
and how we could use some help and for
those that want it it can also be an
accountability session we say what you
can get done before the next meeting
um and uh and we'll be happy to hold you
accountable politely
um so it's kind of a mastermind
it follows the mastermind protocols and
some other things we did and then kind
of an open discussion
uh we do sometimes put if someone's
willing to be on the hot seat
we'll focus in on their project or
specific problem they are
having in their project and we'll all
work together to try and
put them in the right direction
so who would like to start us off
i can't i guess since i'm the one that's
not a mute um
so my project is wiki election is a
project to fight misinformation in
politics
science and news i've actually been
working with mateusz and bentley
to uh come up with the prototype so that
what won't be sort of the full the
full-fledged you know
all all the features it should at least
help
show what the end result should end up
sort of
look looking like and behaving like
and uh the goal here is to actually
start to populate it with some real
information and then just start to build
up the feature set
um i have an idea for something that i
might be able to be in the hot seat for
not sure how long that conversation is
but uh if anyone else has something more
more pressing that's also fine as well
i guess for what i'd be doing for you
know over the next week just
continuing to work with motush on
getting it uh
coded out um and then uh working on the
specs for the next round so once this
round is
uh done to be able to have the next
changes all specked out so that we can
just sort of keep
an assembly line of software going
all right who's next
or two you should carry since i did the
intro
uh okay the project so i'm working on
some
piece of software to visualize and
map data and the shortest description
which is uh yeah it's very short and
like on purpose so it's uh
going well um and hopefully tonight i
will
make a little presentation and if you
are around
that would be awesome cool
yeah and depending on the results
um well i will continue working on it
and
hopefully sooner rather than later uh
it will be like ready to unleash it onto
the public
hopefully yeah
[Music]
okay i'm working on third place which is
a
craft pub idea um i'm getting further on
with my plans and that
so hopefully have something to show for
it soon um
i've been getting in contact with people
who've ran pubs who
like the idea of what i'm doing because
it
pubs are used to be the social the
social network before there was any
any internet any computers uh it was
either the pub or the church people used
to go to
and you'd find the most interesting
people in the pubs but obviously you're
getting drunk on that so um i've been
talking to someone who
reached out to on via donut economics
because i've been looking at
donor economics as a way of sort of like
running things as well
and so we reached out to somebody who i
met on one of the forums and that so i
had a good chat with them
and i think the marketing is going to be
i think i think marketing with
everything so maybe if we could have a
chat about
marketing um maybe rather than do a hot
seat because like
as i said the guy i spoke to he's
friends with the the guy who did the the
marketing for blue dog
and they did sort of like a massive
crowdfunder to get the stuff
together so um yeah so i think if we can
have a chat about marketing
because that seems to affect everybody
have i just gone slow
that's good
anything else carrie let me interrupt
you
okay uh so my project is goaliebot
um i've been saying reason score but
goaliebot's kind of the public facing
of it right now it uses recent scores of
technology in the backend
anyway so goaliebot is a online
bot chat bot it's actually all human
operated
but what he does is well it's not a he
what it does is um
is it builds mass agreement
through online discourse using
reason and evidence
is the goal whether it will do that we
don't know
uh so what i did this week is i got the
the websites just had a coming soon for
months while i work on other stuff
and now it actually has a description of
who goalie bot
is and what gollybot does and then i
did some tweets trying to start
have a debate about nutrition science
and i got crickets
which i didn't reach out to a whole
bunch of people and i didn't really
reach into my network
so that's okay but i think this week i'm
going to try and y'all can help hold me
accountable on this
to go ahead and have a public uh an
open debate on whether we should be
sending the kids back to school
i probably need to narrow it down to the
us to make it manageable
but the debate could be instructive to
other
municipalities i think also we're kind
of the worst
doing the worst with coronavirus right
now i think that's what i hear but that
may be our news media extra
exaggerating things but uh so would
probably be the the
most contentious discussion um so
start a debate on that put it through
the system and
learn from it
would be my next steps and then on the
side i'm prototy to prototyping to
apps for other startups that are not
neither of them are are
high profit startups so
they're just kind of project ideas and
doing some prototypes
and i'm thinking about doing some
uh demos of some profile projects
so just stuff i've wanted to do that i
could show on my profile like
one is telling you what's the best time
to run
during the day based on your own
parameters doing that for my mom who
goes walking
and stuff like that so that's that's
also kind of what i'm working on
um i don't think i have any hot seat
stuff so we could talk about the
marketing or
adriel if yours is kind of if you think
yours is quick we could start yours and
then hit
marketing after that sure and it's kind
of marketing adjacent anyway
and also a little bit touches on
something that i think you're
maybe dealing with
so mine has to do with and i think sort
of briefly touched on this topic
internally before and now it seems like
it's
coming up quick um so part of it is
i think anybody that sort of attended uh
multiple of these and heard me talk
about
wiki election a couple times the end
goal is it'll cover a lot of things
um and i was
it's sort of always been grappling with
the challenge of trying to do too much
under
one umbrella and where maybe the name
book election doesn't actually make
sense
um and and part of it came up yesterday
with the part to track organizations
so what i'm thinking of is there was
another um
i guess brand or company or i don't know
what to call it
that uh i've got the the domain name for
i kind of like the name of and it makes
sense in context of everything
called converati and
the end goal was to maybe have a
different site it's a part of the same
sort of data set
where wiki election is focused on
politics right so there's
uh politicians and parties and you know
where they get their donations from and
what legislation
they're they're passing you know what
lobbying groups they're
they're working with that sort of thing
and then for conferrati have that be
more for the organizations
so like what companies are there who's
on the board um
possibly things like how they paid their
staff and you know what kind of
environmental impact they have but then
also some of that overlap with
wikilection on like how involved is that
is that organization in politics what
sort of donations have they given
especially for lobbying groups what kind
of legislation have
have they affected uh so that you can
sort of see two sides of that same coin
i think in both canada and the us
companies can get pretty involved in the
process and spend a lot of money and
trying to affect legislation
and being able to see what's happening
on both sides there like so for
you know on work election being able to
see
um where a politician's
donations are are coming from like
especially which industry
and then see which legislation
or i guess how they lean on legislation
that that affects
industries especially the ones that
contributed to them you know to show
who's
heavily swayed by donations
and so the the question is sort of about
having
one versus multiple brands like having
it split up
like that or both just from the public
like
do people find that confusing does it it
make more sense
and from this sort of a project
standpoint does it make sense to have
two
very similar projects that sort of thing
which is sort of where i think it sounds
a bit like what you're dealing with
bentley
with bruising score and gully bot where
it's kind of two sides of the same
coin but it's two different things to to
to to talk about
yeah i think i'm um i did it kind of the
opposite way
so reason score is kind of a big tool
and now i'm narrowing it down to one of
the
focuses of one of the use cases and you
did wiki election
which is focusing on the political and
now you're trying to decide whether you
should
do the larger thing um i
i think the good thing about khan
ferrari is that it could mean any
almost anything yeah so you could do
wiki election under that
moniker if you had to um
martu should have to speak to this but i
don't think it'd be that difficult
technically
to serve the same thing to both sites
and maybe have one
maybe start in a different area so if
it's not too much of a technical thing
and you already own the domain
then i would i think it'd probably be a
good idea if
you're feeling passionate about the the
business
one
so i think that's a good idea go ahead
yeah it's just an entry point domain
name is an entry point to the software
and this is exactly the same what i am
doing with hyperlogos
the software is the same and it works
not on the same database maybe but it's
configurable to the point of
you have just one set of files and
different databases for different
entry points and uh it's really easy to
um see what uh domain was used to enter
the site
and then present uh even slightly
different front-end
and possibly slightly different angle to
view the data
right yeah and then
like it would end up sharing data if you
think you know if maybe there's ten
tables
each one might use like seven of them
it can and in this specific case
probably it even should because it's
going to
um all different angles are going to
work on the same
set of people for example instead of
political parties
companies and and so on so it makes
sense to share data
some data at least uh users like
internal users
that can be kept separate so it's it's
all doable and it's all pretty
uh easy to do so no problem
okay cool thank you all right
okay yeah because i'd like i'd be more
interested in the companies actually and
i also wanted to know
um does wiki election include all the
lobby groups
as well as the politicians that's
yes and that's one of the weirder areas
where they kind
the lobbying groups kind of need to
exist on both sides and that's
really one of the only groups that do
like i i
don't expect the political parties to
exist on conferrati
but lobbying groups have to be both yeah
because if you look at a lobbying group
on
wikileaks inside it's very focused on
politics you know and
which like which you know still which
industries do do they get their money
from
but largely based on what legislation
are they trying to affect what
um possibly which politicians have they
made the biggest
donations to you know with the the
emphasis
on what role is that lobbying group
playing in politics
and then on the organization side it
would be heavily involved with
which industries are they involved with
which you know uh
like executives right like on the
business side
sort of yeah which organizations and
which industries are they getting
their money from and they'll you'll see
information from the other side but the
emphasis will be on
what that window is so if we're gone
friday it'll be the organization
and for wiki election it's how they're
affecting politics yeah because i don't
know whether
is there anyone watching them because i
remember watching a documentary
about lobby groups in up until then i've
never heard of them
and the amount of money they get spent
on these lobby groups and for them to to
get in and actually sway
decisions and bills and stuff like that
as well
it's quite disgusting really and
i believe that problem is either
entirely unique or mostly unique to the
us yeah
well i know for the uk and there was a
big huh
uh i can't remember that many years ago
but they got colored some people got
colored
uh cash for questions and stuff like
that so they got they got hold out by
the newspapers which probably
end up paying the price
i don't know whether it was a setup or
whatever but i know there's lots of
groups i don't know whether they're
called lobby groups
or or whatever but for the uk i think
they're probably in every country sway
in every government regardless
i mean so i don't think it i think us i
guess
one of the differences i think might be
in the us i think there's sort of two
different types of lobbying groups
there's you know like the
moms against x where it's
in theory more like citizen focused and
they're
kind of just trying to be a group of
people trying to affect legislation in a
certain direction
personally i guess that's
industry comes together and they all put
money in a pot and then that pod is used
to affect
legislation that massively benefits
their industries
yeah and from what i've heard these
studies in the us on those lobbying
groups
are the single biggest return on
investment
that like it's the the best one of any
action that a company
can currently take like it's an
over-the-top massive roi
so of course companies are going to to
do that
yeah because it's funny because like um
over in the uk you know you get
some of these mps and they've got
business interests
in various companies and and they're the
ones putting through bills for stuff
they're on boards of this that and the
other and you don't know
who's on what boards you know i mean
like like say for example edinburgh
council
just announced like um
so many million pounds of cuts
yeah tesco's jordan the pandemic
um was given so like 600 million
so but like the the people helping
so like you know i mean and cuts towards
everything and then
yeah the money's going to hotels and
tourist industry while all the services
i think
there's a package of 15.9 million of
cuts to be
gone across the board and all the
different services in
edinburgh uh but they give 600 million
to
tesco who's you know you know i mean
it's just ridiculous really yeah and so
then like
if i hear that i wonder okay so first of
all how much has tescos contributed to
either individual politicians or
lobbying groups that are pushing things
or just do certain politicians have ties
to something directly
and both are important
it's about having sort of as many data
points as possible
to uncover that sort of conflict of of
interest or
you know things that might be swaying
politicians that
shouldn't be because just because
somebody contributed to your campaign
sort of you know financially and
tit-for-tat it makes sense
but democratically it doesn't right it's
okay
so yeah and that is a one of the
challenges with all having two domains
is it's like with something like
lobbying
how does that show across each and i
think that might
end up being could you not do it all
under the same debate
of comfort arty i could yeah but i just
think that
election i mean it could end up being
like that wiki election is a tool
offered by conferrati and uh
but for now i think it makes sense to
have two different
domains and also two different brands
because that helps i think with like if
i'm doing
uh if i'm doing marketing towards each
then right the conversation around
what wiki election is more about you
know keeping politicians honest
and holding them into account and
setting up a permanent record
organizations is largely about you know
having information about them so you can
decide who you want to do business with
right yeah yeah and the
audience for them would be other
businesses or would they be just
considered citizens and consumers right
it also for confront it won't just be
politics right it'll also be like
how environmentally aware is this
company right like are they known to uh
you know
use wash green wash whatever
exactly right anything that you as a
consumer would want
to know based on what information is
available there's still problems
how do they pay their employees right
yeah
exactly and then because right now like
with example that kerry gave right with
what are certain companies doing during
the pandemic you have some that are
are sort of using this as an excuse
somehow to justify paying their
employees less
and you know try and scroll in where a
company is profitable but still trying
to
take a really big slice of the pie for
what the government is trying to do to
help
and then big companies come in and take
maybe more than they should
like in the us with the pvp loans there
were some big
companies that were quite profitable
that were have found to you know
have gotten hundreds of millions of
dollars while small companies
the pvp loans ran out before they could
get theirs
yeah the big companies had the advantage
of you know having an
in in the various groups to know sort of
how to effectively get themselves to the
front of the line and they did that and
they got a bunch of money but some of
them were actually shamed into giving
the money back
good which is interesting right because
that seems to be
one of the number one things that can
actually affect the behavior of a gaming
corporation
is the public saying um no if you do
that we aren't
going to give you business anymore
yeah but a lot of people really just
don't give at all so like like take for
example amazon
you know i mean just just how much
amazon's kind of
increased and and listening to sort of
like more about what uber do
and you know they've got no you know
it's just various things i because the
more i look into sort of like businesses
and corporations and that the most
sickened i get by what they're allowed
to get away with
and but then again i suppose all stems
back to the monetary system if you tell
people
how the monetary system actually works
because they still believe that just you
know that's
everything you know and you just get
your cash for your wages and that's it
and a lot of people just still believe
that because they can see the physical
cash
but they don't see this the back end of
it and i don't know whether it's just
that they don't care but i'm sure if you
you taught more people how it actually
worked and spoke the language that
they'd actually believe and how it
affects them
i i'd be they'd be bigger riots
um and people just wouldn't have it you
know i mean so
yeah part of part of the problem though
is that so many people are
busy living it's they're exhausted
so a site like this would lower the
friction to shopping more
because you may like hear oh yeah amazon
or walmart's not paying the customers or
put local businesses out there but like
how much are they if they weren't there
would someone else do it
and then what's an alternative where can
i go so
right if conferrati can make that easier
then
we would might be able to shift um
you know it would never be 100 of people
but yeah it might be more
yeah totally and a part of the goal is
to track it on as many elements as
possible
so that you can decide what what you
care about right because if the site is
trying to make
these value calls for you they're like
who who are these people trying to tell
me
how to spend my money but if you can
tell it how you want to spend your money
and
all it says is okay so based on what
you've said you care about here's how
those companies score
like one of the important things in the
us
at least for me that like i want to be
available
is the effective tax rate that that
company has paid
right okay because most of them have
loopholes they as i said
like these methods that not only pay
zero in tax but that then get
various you know incentives and like
and uh and subsidies and
and stuff like that to say hey so this
company made x
they paid their you know executives this
way they pay their staff that way
they have this sort of subsidies and
they pay no tax
you can decide if that means anything to
you if maybe it's just one piece
or if you want to see sort of that whole
piece of the financial pie
and then the end goal would sort of be
hey here's the you know some of their
main competitors
that score higher based on what you said
you care about
so if you're looking at amazon and
there's some alternatives
and you're looking at amazon it might
say here's their score and here's some
of the scores of their
their competitors right okay
all right so kind of like our
conversation yesterday on the
alternative to and caftera but like
starting out with corporations instead
of pro
instead of their products yeah which
okay for amazon that one we might want
to split down into sort of multiple
levels just because amazon does so many
things
yeah they've got the fingers and loads
of pies eh
i just used amazon for a website demo ah
shave on your belly shave on you it's
the quickest and easiest way to get it
up
and it's for free i'm not i'm actually
not paying them any money i'm using the
resources so there
okay um and i but although i do buy like
it is one thing i've been people
wondering about since state gaming since
joining gay bay right
there's a lot of tech people who were
kind of responsible
for developing algorithms for nefarious
companies
and and that and now now they're in
there and now they're all going oh but i
want to make the world a better place
so then being complicit and now coming
to the table saying oh
you know maybe a show yeah you know
you know yeah that's true and there is a
there is a movement from within
these companies to make change and
there's a guy who i can't remember
which of the large companies he worked
for but he was pretty high up and he's
quit and he now has a podcast talking
about
it's more of the social media ones about
how the social media is having these
negative effects to the
algorithms and such like that and he was
one of the guys that wrote one of the
algorithms
or was part of that uh yeah there's like
sting
and with uh google some sort of
andrew the andrew wang or someone i
don't remember
and saying just basically yeah you know
um yeah and you also got to think that
you know our culture is that you know
you go and you get a job and you do what
they ask you to do
and you don't really before recently it
wasn't much thought into it and also
many of them didn't think oh that i'd be
throwing elections
by yeah
on the the project board they then be
like hey jim we're going to have you
work on algorithm that's going to skew
the election
yeah right they they just say hey you're
going to be on here's
the specs and then the person that
designed it honestly
i would say three-quarters of the time
they don't even know how other groups
are going to use it they're just
building a feature that sounds neat
yeah well well that's going to be funny
what obsessed me about these algorithms
about
about that is um well what
one of the the finance companies does
this year share
prices and um to do with that and there
was a young guy who ended up killing
himself
because these algorithms said seven
million
robin hood which that one was weird
because that wasn't even actual money
that was like a testing
account that they used to help people
um learn yeah how people learn how to
invest so he was
dealing with fake money i guess one day
i think that may have actually
been a bug like where he had you know
some good money one day and then he woke
up and he was negative seven million
yeah i guess that just hit him in super
because he knew it was
just training
like now you're seven million in debt
you know what i mean it it it was fake
and it sounded like he knew that i think
he was probably just
depressed and that was the thing that
that
said but yeah that's weird because
that's actually a tool that's meant to
help
people who wouldn't otherwise learn how
to invest learn how to invest what's
actually trying to help like
people in poverty because that's you
know in game a that's
one of the areas where if you know what
you're doing with investments
that's something that they can actually
help with out of poverty
the issue is that you're gambling right
yeah okay and adrian can you
uh pull up i think it's probably it's
jubilee's facebook
uh comment the last one yeah so she's
saying she talked to mark campbell we'll
be hosting solution ratings on vote with
your wallet
so that will fit um everything that we
were discussing in the last meeting and
then
you know moving uh with the focusing
focus instead of wiki election more to
the conference and doing that
right i'd also like to say that i i
think uh
if martius is going to be coding this up
or
if i might be helping because this is
something
i've been passionate about is also to
kind of build the software in such a way
that it doesn't matter what it is
uh that people can a community can come
together
figure out what the things the rank
things are and then score them as a
group
so whether it ends up because that same
code could be used for the politicians
could be used for the corporations could
be used for products
you know so totally abstracting that
out and make it customizable um
i might be putting work in martia's
conference will end up being the
umbrella for a lot of projects like that
because it's kind of
i think as you said it kind of doesn't
mean anything particularly like
the the root word sort of dress me like
a system for discussion or like a system
for sort of
figuring out who you want to do business
sounded a bit conspiratorial though
[Laughter]
she was like confederati i was like no
there's no d
but i think it'd probably take off
jubilee's comment oh yeah
i think it's one of those made up words
that you know
sounds weird until it takes off and then
it just becomes a word that everyone
knows
okay blaming's yeah
all right so do you want to talk about
marketing then
marketing strategies
right go ahead okay so so i think um
i don't know who would be the best
person to ask
in terms of marketing strategies but i
do feel like we kind of need somebody
but it could maybe sort of like help guy
just develop some market strategies for
projects that are being done
um and i think maybe help us build kind
of plans and guides
or even direct us in the the right
places because
what i'm seeing on facebook just now is
is you know a torrent
of we could teach you this marketing
strategy if you just
you know sign up for this sign up for
that give us all your money and we'll
tell you how to
start your own business and market it to
all the right people
and and i'm i'm part of a few of them
which are kind of watch
you know because some of the comments
are just hilarious they should be on a
comedy show
but it's just that nefarious ways oh get
them to do this and get them to do that
i think you just touched on one of the
biggest challenges for this group
is all of those marketing resources are
for
for-profit companies right so it's not
about like it's all
it's weirdly not usually about getting
an audience they just
directly skew it as how to make money
how to get
followers that you can then monetize
like yeah
i think a lot of the tactics are useful
and some aren't i think it'd be
interesting to
do i don't know the time for this um and
i know this a little bit i'm not a
marketing expert so i guess
to carry's point we're putting the
callouts anyone who's watching this are
going to watch this later
if you understand marketing or social
media like for marketing
or just general you know any of those
things then we would like to work with
you to
build a resource like kerry said for all
the game b
projects to give them a resource i think
we'll probably post that as a request to
the main
channel yeah because basically um
right so we want marketing strategies
for
companies and organizations that don't
extract value from human
beings so how are we gonna are we
are we actually gonna do that without
doing that well there are
a lot of the tactic some of the target
i'd say good half the tactics can be
used in both game a
and game b totally uh although it's
interesting we might
someone who's been thinking about it for
a while might be able to find some
strategies that work for game b
that don't work for game a that have
been ignored because
there's not been a room for it yeah or
they weren't as profitable
even though they were right yeah but i
think apparently
just a minute ago you touched on what we
probably would end up needing to do
which is like there's sort of the
different areas and marketing is a huge
umbrella
like when peop when most i think people
think marketing
what they're actually saying is
advertising but there's so much more to
it looks like there's market research
there's
the positioning there's all these pieces
right and
i think it might end up being uh you
know a library of maybe 10 topics that
like okay so what do you need help with
when you say marketing
are you trying to expand your audience
where it's just i
i'm trying to tell that sort of one
one directional story where you know you
telling a story through
blog posts and advertising and whatever
where you're crafting a message that you
then
want to send out to a bunch of people to
help you know to to get them interested
that's absolutely one of the areas that
even in game b is still useful
is that sort of storytelling and how do
you craft that message to to get people
interested
that's something that i think all of our
projects need help with so so basically
we need to develop
a propaganda unit that's basically what
we have to do
so they propaganda for good though so
we're talking about
names propaganda may not be the best
name for a game be marketing maybe
propaganda
[Music]
i mean propaganda is really just one
type of kind of
advertising or like it's kind of a goal
of
marketing but but basically overall
advertising and his propaganda
um you know because if you look back in
history through to edward bernays
got all these um posh bit beds on the
street smoking fags torches of freedom
and all that and you're just like well
and that made it okay for women to smoke
because
women weren't smoking up to that point
but as i said get all these debutants on
the street
going oh look at me smoking my torches
and freedom
you know and they all went oh i want
some of that because you know what i
mean
um so is it because i was listening to
something and they basically said i
think it as i said i think it was johnny
dotton from the sex pistols
and he was on this talk show and that
and he said basically you've got to
take the tools what they use and fight
them and use their own tools against
them
which that i think is kind of the at the
very core of game b
is to out complete using the advantages
i'm going to put
chili's comment over saying vote with
your dollar app
is also the the real marketing used for
two maker
information with no lies and not a
single marketing strategy
which so a big part of marketing
is understanding the market and there i
think are
um there is a real need for people
to understand it and of course they all
have sort of
different reasons for
what they're supporting and then there's
also just things like well it's close by
to me
so even if they don't necessarily
support the things i care about if
they're my only option i still need to
eat
right okay and then there's you know it
might be sort of on that same vein
well i don't want to deal with walmart
or amazon or
whoever but they're the only company in
my
city offering this thing or you might
have to choose between
walmart and amazon and you don't want to
either you're like but which dude do i
pick
so i think it is an important element i
wouldn't say the only one
but i personally hope in in the coming
years that it becomes the most important
one
and that people are always sort of using
that to to weigh in
and there's a bunch of things that you
could do like with browser extensions
and whatnot
to sort of always have that information
be available because even on something
like
like amazon it could be okay here's
amazon score
but also you're trying to buy something
from this company on amazon so now we're
talking about at least two companies
amazon
and whoever makes that thing is your
technically supporting
them as well do you want both okay
i just noticed that an app i was i'd
seen before but they weren't out so i
wasn't sure whether they actually did
what they say uh but you can
pop my screen up if you want just while
we're on the discussion oh
yeah there we go yeah so this is
boycott.com
b-o-b-y-c-o-t-t by calling.
but yeah it's basically the ability to
boycott now i think this is more
campaign based as opposed to you know
you do a
yeah this one's campaign based it but it
does allow you to search by
upc symbol and stuff like that so
depending on what
um what your
flavor is uh so that's interesting that
that i think this came out fairly
recently because i saw it a couple
months ago and i wasn't sure if it was
going to be a thing or not
uh yeah so that's an option yeah
i think that's a very good good start
and uh i mean i'm always a fan of having
sort of
multiple irons in the fire because
there's always a chance that one project
will end up failing so if something like
con ferrari doesn't take off
i definitely want to know that you know
it's not the only option out there
yeah so
and i think i think somebody touched on
it a bit earlier
with the one of the important parts to
work with the public on is sort of what
are the things you care about
that should end up being scored because
i i know
in the uh the prototypes i'm working
with
my tucson i've just got sort of six
vague metrics that i'll end up scoring
on for
the prototype but in the end version it
needs to you know
there's going to be a nearly infinite
number of
sort of the different categories and
subcategories like there might be
you know the very broad environmentalism
and that could break down into like okay
water pollution and air pollution and
you know th they themselves
might not make that much pollution but
they make a lot of stuff out of plastic
which then ends up being
pollution all that sort of thing where
it's all
under the same umbrella but also you may
want to be able to
drill down and say well i don't believe
that this particular part of
environmental environmentalism is that
important but these two are
and that whole system so carried you
talked about a kind of a generic kind of
game b
marketing toolkit um but i'd but i also
think in the short term
anyone who has a project that they want
marketing we should do a project raising
for and just have that
be the focus and also if you want to
for the rest of time here we can do that
just because i i do have from working in
startups and trying to do my own stuff i
have some marketing experience
um and may and other people also can
give you feedback on your marketing
ideas
right um so we could try and focus on
the specific struggle that brought this
up also for the rest of the time
here if you like yeah well well as i
said there's a lot of
like good ideas and there's good stuff
but it's just how it gets
marketing seems to be the stumbling
block for about it just about everybody
and i know sort of like ivana was
talking about um crowdfunding and
different crowdfunding and
equity this and i can see that and
there's a whole range of things
that are out there um but as i said if
you only tell you they only give you
guides of
oh come and do this with us and that but
they don't tell you the pitfalls like
hey you need
a huge network of people be you need
solid relationships built
c and you need to be able to spam your
network
about three times a day because as i
said one of my friends did one for an
art exhibition
he wasn't an artist he just decided he
was going to do an art exhibition
and and that and he managed to raise all
the money but what he ended up doing was
having to
keep up people every day you know what i
mean
and let them know and keep them updated
and as i said it's kind of like a
full-time job
and you know to me so like if i didn't
know him
i would have just clicked off it and
gone oh you know what i'm sick of it and
i've heard from you
you know what i mean so what's the fine
line of sort of like
panicking to sort of get the money
because as i said
my thing with kickstarter was if you
didn't raise the money you didn't
you didn't raise all the money that you
didn't get anything
and i thought well you've just you've
just spent maybe the past
two months of spamming all your friends
neighbors anybody
talking to them you know money grabbing
sort of like from
from that amount of time and you've not
raised it so all
that effort has gone into nothing you
know because as i said
i've given to two that have you know
completed
and that there was two that failed and
they were mostly graphic novels
and stuff like that so they learned a
lot but as i said
you know it puts the relationships that
they've got with people in jeopardy
so as i said that's why
that's one of the marketing techniques
that works
and that's probably the most popular but
it's not the only
yeah and that's becoming less and less
popular the whole like kind of
slash and burn i just need to make it
through this project
which you know i think in the corporate
world like an example of that is cold
calling
yeah where it's like you find somebody's
email phone number you're like well
i have their information fair game which
first of all in a lot of cases is now
illegal
but companies still do it yeah i
remember i remember going to work for
them ipsos money which is kind of like a
polling thing and we have to
do cold calls and it was just like
i've gone through the training i was all
right through the training i was doing
really well
and i think him i'd started at 12 i was
out the door by two
i was like nah nah i can't do i can't do
this i can't be bothering people
with stuff about this you know i mean i
just i just can't and
you know it's not even like trying to
sell them stuff
i don't know it's just pulling
you know what i mean i'd get sworn out
i'd get the phone put down on me
and you know they got to the stage when
i was just like
i can't bother people that much you know
i mean because that's you know you
you're bothering people and as i said my
friends he does um
tells double glazing and that and i
don't know how he's managed to last
because he normally does six months and
that and then he has to go and do
something else
because i'm like i i don't know dennis
how you could do that you know because
as i said i've tried various call center
jobs and the the most
horrifying jobs that you've got to have
targets you can't talk to people
for such a time as well you know what i
mean and it's just they're just
horrendous places to work
you know and even if you've just got the
incoming course you're dealing with the
horrendous places to work you know i
mean
so just the idea of having to sort of
like bother people
it really bothers me that someone would
expect you to actually do that you know
i mean so um
i'd like to find a marketing campaign
where you didn't have to bother anyone
well yeah i mean the other the other
common one is actually
creating a landing page and buying ads
and then testing out the different
landing pages
but that right that contends on your
ability to
express the idea and it has to be an
idea that people can understand quickly
and are willing to support
so i mean the better there are ideas
that are so good
that you don't that you know your two
three friends will tell
two three friends yeah that's all you
need to do um
it's it's this area where
the ideas are getting more difficult
that you either have to put in more
money or you have to
drain your network right okay yeah
so i'm trying to think of like what the
highest level groupings for marketing
are
and the three i have is sort of like the
the really early days
in a project trying to understand what
the market wants how you want to
position your
you you your project um which i think a
lot of people don't really think of when
they think of marketing but
in a good project that's typically what
you'll start with
is the like you know even something like
what you call it
what problem are you actually trying to
solve if you know like generally
right like for example with wiki
election if my goal is to fight
misinformation we'll keep it where
because that's it
it affects a lot of areas so i started
with politics but i
could have started in any number of
areas and
where with bentley he's positioning
reasons for sort of you know
a tool to help navigate that that
conversation to be able to say hey
anybody that's trying to solve this kind
of a problem here's sort of a tool that
you can help use to do that
and he may word it differently than that
but but based on what you know
he said and what he's shown that's what
i get out of it so there's sort of
the positioning piece whereas just
figuring out
what story to tell who your you know who
your audience is who
you you you're going after then the next
step is usually to build
your audience in some cases that's sort
of combined with
the next step but with a lot of projects
like ours you start out you know with a
facebook group or
or something where your end goal is just
to see okay did
did i do step one right if i tell the
story do people get interested
yeah developing them stories and
you think the main thing first
developing a story
yeah yeah you got to know you got to
well usually the first step is to narrow
your audience
because almost everyone unless they're
experienced
their audience like well everyone can
use my tool well if you explain
it like that no one will because that
people don't see
themselves using you know using your
tool using a product going to it
unless they unless it feels like it's
it's meant for them and it's not meant
for everybody it's just the
it's an unfortunate habit of the human
brain so
yeah figuring out your audience and then
there's different ways to reach in
there's advertising there's content
marketing so if you start creating blog
posts and you share them around and you
you get your blog posts on other sites
that have high seo and that's part of
seo
marketing also so i i know there's a
thing called relationship marketing as
well
so i know that's kind of i suppose i'm
kind of like because i like building
relationships now
and yeah although i don't know that i
would see relationship marketing
it can be done well but it's still a
miss
right so i mean that's multi-level
marketing is
is a one form of i don't like that
right right so that's that's
relationship
that's one form of it there are other
forms that are less okay
but in general relationship marketing
ends up
and actually honestly that's what you
were you were saying the the thing
for um that's what using your network is
that's relationship marketing
yeah right okay it really depends on the
cost of your
the the price uh if we're talking game a
the
the the your your lifetime
value of each customer so the total
money they give you
and then the cost to acquire and then
you have to forge your salary in there
as far as those relationships so usually
like building a strong relationship with
an individual person only works for
um products that are over you know a
thousand dollars per purchase or 700
a month but so
for something like where you're building
a tool like me or adriel then
um content marketing creating videos
creating blog posts that
follow up on seo and doing some seo
marketing to
to build more content marketing is
probably because we'll reach more people
with fewer hours
yeah but building that story is
important because if you put out the
wrong content
you're going to get you know you got to
have i suppose
with what i'm doing though i suppose
relationship marketing's gonna have to
fit into that
because it's gonna be way too much
they're actually bringing people to the
drop-in
craft thing and stuff like that as well
yeah so
um i know i'm gonna have to use it for
that with almost
all of this there there's going to end
up being like
uses that i will will probably find
unacceptable and those that we don't
right but marketing for the most part is
just navigating how humans actually
operate
they've done tons of research to say how
do people make d d
decisions what gets and keeps their
attention
all sorts of things that we still have
to navigate within the realms of how do
people actually operate yes
somebody said propaganda for good
pfg have we done a project raising on
your project yet
we haven't um no but as i said what what
i was gonna do
because of the because me me drop-ins
got stopped after to week two
part of me thing was right was to get so
like get that back on the go
because like i've been running them for
well till they told me to sod off really
um
and i know it was was not about bringing
money in this was all about building
relationships with people in the
community
um so that's coming along well as i said
once you want to get the
the churches wait until phase four of
the lockdown to go back into it and then
that's that
but also i'll speak to a guy um who
responded to one of me posts and that
and he was in
um because because all these big pub
companies are basically taking over all
like as i said pubs used to be the hub
of sort of like social life in the uk
and i don't know whether that's been
anywhere else but in the uk
there used to be a pub on every corner
and you know people would be
various running them and you'd go and
have your pub friends
who you'd only see in the pub you'd
never see anywhere else
you never see them outside you just see
them in the pub it's like they just live
there you know what i mean so
so there's a whole social aspect of that
and then hubs get shut down they get
taken over
but like you've got these companies like
punch
and these other to buy out all these
pubs and then they offered them back
to to you know low cost anyone could run
their own pub
throughout being that yeah so um and
then they do that to people and then the
people
they just they're just after the money
from the pub from the beer
so they have to take on their beard so
he's not allowed to do any local beers
not allowed to do this that the other
and what what goes away from that is
because they
have to be focused on keeping the place
open the the the desperation that they
have on running after people to sort of
try and get the money
you don't really care whether people
come in they just came with the the
you know they get slaughtered by the
beer and that's basically it so the
social aspect
of all that has gone now and i was
listening to someone saying there's no
public spaces
where people can actually gather unless
they're a corporation
already business you know you've got to
give us money before you can actually go
so
so part of me thing was to try and make
it so yes i know it needs to wash its
face
but yes i want to offer a place for
people to gather
members of the public that you know
they're not gonna
you know want to come in they can have a
cup of tea that's fine
um i'm gonna have to find different
revenue streams
of finding out of to make that that
happen
and i've got to write a plan and take
all that in mind
but as i said i was looking at donut
economics and i realized you know you've
got the
local the global and then you've got the
social and the economic
and i know that's just kind of a 30 at
the moment but i'm going to try and do
the plan out of that
but obviously the it's the nondominium
which adrian laughed at me last time
when i said it's nondividing like a
condominium
but we're going to go after that model
and as i said the guy he was talking to
he's he's he's got a network of all
these people who run pubs and
uh and the pubs are dying on their feet
because they're like they're closing
down all the time
and as i said cafes are opening up but
they're after the
the money and that so um he's got a big
network of people there
and i was talking to him for about two
hours today
he was telling me what he was doing and
it was along the same lines
as what i was doing and and then i've
got somebody else going to talk to one
of the chairmen of this local
town council planning or whatever about
what what we're doing and seeing if
there's any empty spaces and that
because i lost out
to the one because they're going to be
built in flats but that's fine
but if you can manage to find one place
to do this
in and i think that'll be a game changer
for
the rest of them because as i said i'd
be quite happy because i've got people
all
up and down the uk as well in other
places
who'd be interested in maybe setting
setting them up but as i said i just
need to start one
and make that work make that wash its
face to be able to go to
and help other people set up to give
them a bit of open saying yeah that can
so i i think um in terms of solution
reasons
um i just i just need help with planning
because i'm shite at that writing down
like i said i said i could talk the legs
off donkeys but don't don't make me
write shit down
well yeah and yeah so the so a
video kind of discussion would just
focus on ideas and doing that
and maybe also one of the things could
be asking for someone to kind of help
you
talk to you and then they can write up
the plan yeah we've got about five
minutes left
um so let's kind of open it up to
closing comments and
then if no one has anything we can oh
i'm out there
there's kind of nothing i think that uh
to round out the list i was talking
about there's the like so
there there's the positioning the
building your audience i think the third
one
which is important but i think a lot of
people in this group are hesitant to
talk about or even use this term is
monetization
it's taking your your your audience and
not even necessarily just modernization
but like a call to action
where for something like wikilection
eventually i'm going to need to
crowdsource because i my end goal is to
not take any corporate money
which means that it has to come from
somewhere and so that's things like
patreon and kickstarter
or some things that might be you know
actually selling an item like for for
cubespawn
i think the plan there is to actually
sell the cubes that spawn
um but that's a whole avenue in itself
which i think has some negative
connotations
but the projects have to keep the lights
on and so it's
finding that balance in admitting that
you have to make money
but not having that be your sole purpose
i think a good word for that is
sustainability
because we want our products to exist
and we want them to continue exist
although part of me is a little scared
of that because our projects should only
exist for the extent that they're
valuable
right if suddenly we solve government
issues
we won't need a wiki election not that
that's going to happen
in your case but like let's say we were
trying to solve for poverty and we get
ubi
installed and there's and and that kind
of really solves it then
if it does which i'm not saying it will
um then you would want to close down
that project and people can go find
something valuable
but yeah but making something
sustainable for as long as it needs i
yeah that would be the game b version of
of monetization
or profit yeah which i think that there
is
a particular conversation around
like you know that particular thing of
trying to to
to to make money where it's
because i think sustainability would i
think that i hear
you know not polluting and like overall
which is still important but i think a
lot of that is also around your
positioning
where in in marketing the modernization
is specifically
getting people involved at various
levels so kind of like the next step for
building your audience and then actually
okay now now that you know a thousand
people are following me on facebook
what do i do with them what's the the
next step
i think part of that might be to make
money but the other part like for
wiki election part of it is just getting
people to sign up and actually add
information
yeah which is not it has yeah
actually yeah that's probably a better
thing because part of that could be
making money but it's also if you
if we just want you to you know to sign
up and sign in and you know
actually use it that's still an
important part
yeah i guess realistically if it's just
an open resource
and the costs are so low for like
in technical stuff and it's all
volunteer then
you may not money may not have to be
involved in one of our projects
um i don't i don't think that's real
possible but i mean it is possible i
don't think it's likely
yeah well and i think that's where one
of
the things that we could do with
together tech is have that be the
umbrella
to sort of handle the okay well if you
want to handle these kind of projects
you just donate
one amount to together tech and then
that group can say okay so what do we
want to fund with this
which then also helps what you're
talking about with the once a project
has lived its purpose
well if together tech is sort of quote
unquote
the owner of that thing then it can have
you know people that know marketing
people that know coding people
this that once the community decides
that's outlived its purpose
you can just stop putting resources on
it or put you know
fewer resources like if we get ubi you
probably still want some people on the
the project almost for like a lobbying
thing because there's going to be people
who still
fight against it and you'll want to make
sure that you're not you know
getting too complacent or people end up
killing it
i think anyway but you would all you
would
definitely not need the same kind of
resources that you had up until that
point
yep i think we've run out of time
i think might you want to chime in
quickly just yeah i just wanted to close
with
um first um sustainability
yes and i don't see it actually ending
because the
there is going to be uh game a
types like always i don't see them just
no
going away anytime soon so uh
there will always be in the foreseeable
future
need to watch them and
track their nasty businesses and
stuff and sustainability also means
something unknown in game a territory
which is
limiting the profits to only what is
actually needed
game is strictly profit as much as
possible
and in this case profit only means that
the network
and infrastructure and people they need
to be
sustained but uh not over
grown to you know not looking for
uh new ways to grow but rather this is
the goal
we need so much uh resources to
uh get to the goal and be able to
um do what we
need to do and what we said we are doing
and
that's it and everything else if it
happens to be
more so to speak profitable then
all the profits would go directly into
the
project itself not as like
reinvesting profits but uh like um
okay this is the surplus of uh resources
so
we can do something nice uh and not just
package it and
you know take away so strict rules of
game b yeah which to me that's
that's one of the only things that to me
makes something not a game b
project is what like is i guess the
opposite of what you're talking about or
if it's rent seeking if it's you know
shareholder
like it's all about shareholder profit
that to me is one of the only things
where you're like
that's game a like straight up that's
pure game
that drives bad behavior almost anything
else
you know you can be a game b your game
be adjacent but that's the only thing in
our conversation around
is it game b that's all i took took out
of it
we all sort of had ideas and we're like
well but there's if sedans and butts but
the the for profit part to me is the one
thing where i'm like okay i don't
really trust that project anymore
if it's set up for profit or if it's set
up especially in a way
where the profit ends up in people's
pockets like the more money that company
makes the more money these people make
that drives that drives bad behaviors as
opposed to
here's how much the project costs to run
here's the the salary that we
we pay employees here's you know the
cost of hosting
anything outside of that stays in the
project or you know goes to something
like uh
a step above like together tech we're
saying hey we have this extra money
what do we want to spend it on all the
staff are still you know
they're making their salaries what do we
want to do with this here's 10 projects
that we could fund that haven't been
able to get their own money
which one of these do we want to help
fund yeah and that can be a long
discussion yeah so cool i think that's
it for today
thanks everyone thank you
bye